Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations
2007-ongoing
WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
219.0 websites
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of national and regional labor unions, as well as departments and divisions of trade unions. Most of the websites captured are either national American unions or New York metropolitan area local unions. Unions represent workers from many different industries, including the service industry, construction, communication workers, transport workers, manufacturing, government, and entertainment industry. Websites contain information on bargaining and agreements, organizing, member benefits, history, legislative activities, event and conference information, news and blog posts, and other union information.
Tamiment Library.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library’s Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.
Related Archival Material
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals
Guide to the Printed Ephemera Collection on Trade Unions (PE 001)
Access Restrictions
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after the initial capture.
Take Down Policy
Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner’s request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of national and regional labor unions, as well as departments and divisions of trade unions. This is an assembled collection, the websites were selected by the archivists. Most of the websites captured are either national American unions or New York metropolitan area local unions. Unions collected in this finding aid represent workers from many different industries, including the service industry, construction, communication workers, transport workers, manufacturing, government, and entertainment industries.
Union websites contain information on their committees, their constitution and by-laws, board members, publications, organizing and mobilization materials, conference materials, member benefits and services, legislative reports and other political action committee materials, information on districts and locals, event listings, and blogs. The websites act to inform their members of their benefits and rights, as well as to create support for their initiatives. Many websites contain information related to strikes and other actions taken up by the unions and document the success and failures of the campaigns. Evidence of union collaboration and mergers are also documented in the web archives.
Other websites in this collection are related to labor education and history, cultural groups, labor festivals, labor legislation lobbying groups, labor action websites, labor councils, labor news websites, job listings, and union products. Many of these organizations are not traditionally unions, but provide support and help to organize workers for better pay, benefits, and representation in the workplace. The collection also aims to document the efforts to organize low-wage service sector workers and minority, immigrant, and female workers.
These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, audio, message boards, and other media. These websites often act to document and update upon the organizations’ activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their cause or organization, information on projects the organizations are working on, and writings and articles by members of the organization.
The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Existence and Location of Originals note
Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.
Accruals note
In general, new crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.
Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project.
Labor movement |x Political activity |z United States.; Labor movement |z United States.; Labor unions |z United States |x History.; Labor unions |z United States.; Labor |z United States.
- 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Archived Website, Jun 18, 2010 - ongoing; Service Employees International Union. Local 1199 (New York, N.Y.).
  Scope and Contents note
  United Healthcare Workers East (1199SEIU), founded in 1932 as the Local 1199, is a local union of the Service Employees International Union, representing more than 300,000 members. Members work in homecare, hospital and nursing home industries, as well as pharmacies, freestanding clinics, and other healthcare settings. The mission of the union is to improve and expand quality patient care, to protect and improve the lives of members and their families, and to work in solidarity with working people in SEIU’s communities and around the world. In 1998, they affiliated to the Service Employees International Union (SEIU). Since 1998, 15 healthcare local unions throughout New York State, New Jersey, the District of Columbia, Florida, Maryland and Massachusetts have merged with 1199SEIU.
  Home health aides |x Labor unions |z United States.; Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; Medical personnel |x Labor unions |z Northeastern States.
- 32BJ Service Employees International Union Archived Website, Apr 5, 2013 - ongoing; Service Employees International Union. Local 32B-32J (New York, N.Y.).
  Service Employees International Union (SEIU), 32BJ is a New York based property service workers union, made up of approximately 120,000 workers (as of this writing in 2013). It was founded in 1921 as the Building Service Employees International Union. In 1968 the union was renamed the Service Employees International Union and in 1977, the Local 32B union had merged with Local 32J. Today, the union's members consists of primarily janitors, property maintenance workers, doormen, security officers, window cleaners, building engineers, and school and food service workers. The website contains a blog, information on the activities of their political action committee, contracts, and campaigns.
  Service industries workers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Service industries workers--New York (State)
- Actors' Equity Association Archived Website, Sep 23, 2007 - ongoing; Actors' Equity Association.
  Actors' Equity Association ("AEA" or "Equity"), founded in 1913, is the labor union that represents more than 48,000 actors and stage managers in the United States. Equity seeks to advance, promote and foster the art of live theatre as an essential component of our society. Equity negotiates wages and working conditions and provides a wide range of benefits, including health and pension plans, for its members. Actors' Equity is a member of the AFL-CIO, and is affiliated with FIA, an international organization of performing arts unions. The website contains their newsletter, Equity News, news listings, member benefits, agreements, election information, and meeting listings.
  Actors |x Labor unions |z United States.; Stage managers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Actors' Fund of America Archived Website, Mar 29, 2009 - ongoing; Actors' Fund of America.
  The Actors Fund, a nonprofit human services organization founded in 1882, serves professionals in film, theater, television, music, opera, and dance through programs that address their professional needs. The Fund serves more than 12,000 performing arts and entertainment professionals across the country every year, and reaches hundreds of thousand through the Fund’s online resources. The Fund operates as a safety net, to provide programs and services, including comprehensive social services, health services, supportive and affordable housing, employment and training services, and skilled nursing and assisted living care for performing arts and entertainment professionals in need. The website contains information on their services and programs, tickets to upcoming performances and events, and education and workshops.
  Actors |z United States |x Societies, etc.; Fraternal organizations |z United States.
- ACT-UAW (UAW Local 7902) Archived Website, Nov 21, 2014-ongoing; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 7902. (New York, N.Y.).
  Scope and Content Note
  ACT-UAW Local 7902 (Adjuncts Coming Together) represents over 4,000 part- time and adjunct teachers at the New School and New York University. The union was formed in 2002 by adjuncts at NYU, which first ratified their first contract in 2004. In 2004, adjuncts at the New School began to negotiate, and reached an agreement with the New School in 2005. The union has successfully negotiated better pay, job security, partially subsidized health care, pension benefits, and promoted transparency within the universities' budgetary systems. The website contains their current contracts, information about their committees and stewards, election results, their newsletter, Adjunct Voice, and a gallery of their members' art.
  New School (New York, N.Y.).; New York University.; College teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- AFL-CIO New York City Central Labor Council Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010 - ongoing; AFL-CIO. New York City Central Labor Council..
  The New York City Central Labor Council (NYCCLC) is a non-profit labor membership organization devoted to supporting, advancing and advocating for the working people of New York City. The NYCCLC brings together 300 local unions from every trade, occupation, public and private sector of the New York economy. The Council represents 1.3 million workers, including teachers, truck drivers, operating engineers, nurses, construction workers, electricians, firefighters, retail workers, janitors, train operators, bakers, and others. NYCCLC is affiliated with the AFL-CIO. The website includes information on the issues that they work on, including healthcare, retirement, employment, education, civil rights, and immigration. The website also contains news and event listings.
  Central labor councils.
- AFL-CIO Working Families Vote 2008 Archived Website, Aug 17, 2009-Mar 9, 2010; AFL-CIO Working Families Vote 2008.
  AFL-CIO Working Families Vote 2008 was an online political action arm of the AFL-CIO for the U.S. 2008 elections.
  Obama, Barack; Elections |z United States |y 2008.; Labor unions |x Political activity |z United States.; Presidents |z United States |x Election |y 2008.
- AFL-CIO.org Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; AFL-CIO.
  The American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO) is a voluntary federation of 56 national and international labor unions. The AFL-CIO was created in 1955 by the merger of the AFL and the CIO. The AFL-CIO union movement represents 12.2 million members, including teachers, miners, firefighters, farm workers, bakers, engineers, pilots, public employees, doctors, nurses, painters, plumbers and other workers
  Labor unions |z United States.
- Air Line Pilots Association (ALPA) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Air Line Pilots Association
  The Air Line Pilots Association, International (ALPA) is the largest airline pilot union in the world and represents nearly 53,000 pilots at 36 U.S. and Canadian airlines. Founded in 1931, the Association is chartered by the AFL-CIO and the Canadian Labour Congress. Known internationally as US-ALPA, it is a member of the International Federation of Air Line Pilot Associations.
  Air pilots |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Albert Shanker Institute Archived Website, Jul 26, 2009 - ongoing; Albert Shanker Institute.
  The Albert Shanker Institute is a nonprofit foundation dedicated to advancing democratic ideals, improving the quality of public education, and conducting research in the labor movement and the sociology of work. The foundation sponsors research, holds roundtable discussions, and publishes various reports. The Institute was named for Albert Shanker (1928-1997), the late president of the American Federation of Teachers.
  Democracy |z United States.; Education |z United States.; Labor unions |z United States.
- Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) Archived Website, Dec 11, 2009 - ongoing; Amalgamated Transit Union
  The Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) is the largest labor organization representing transit workers in the United States and Canada. Founded in 1892, the ATU today is comprised of over 190,000 members in 264 local unions spread across 44 states and nine provinces. Composed of metropolitan, interstate, and school bus drivers; paratransit, light rail, subway, streetcar, and ferry boat operators; mechanics and other maintenance workers; clerks, baggage handlers, municipal employees, and others. The ATU works to promote transit issues and fights for the interests of its hard-working members. ATU is a member the AFL-CIO, and the Canadian Labor Congress (CLC).
  Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181 Archived Website, Jan 16, 2013 - ongoing; Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181
  Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181 is the largest local in the United States for the Amalgamated Transit Union. It represents drivers, escorts, school bus drivers, and mechanics in New York City, Westchester County and Long Island. The website contains information on their school bus strike in 2013, their pension and welfare fund, and a calendar.
  Transport workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x History.; Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Amalgamated Transit Union Local 1555 Archived Website, Oct 22, 2013-ongoing; Amalgamated Transit Union. Local 1555.
  The Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) Local 1555 represents approximately 900 front-line workers of the Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) system in California. The websites contains information on the 2013 BART strike.
  Strikes and lockouts |z United States.; Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE) Archived Website, Dec 8, 2009 - ongoing; American Federation of Government Employees
  The American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE), founded in 1932, is an American labor union representing over 600,000 employees of the federal government, about 5,000 employees of the District of Columbia, and a few hundred private sector employees, mostly in and around federal facilities. Workers in many functions of government at every federal agency depend upon AFGE for legal representation, legislative advocacy, technical expertise and informational services. It is affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  Collective bargaining |x Government employees |z United States.
- American Federation of Musicans, Local 802 Archived Website, Jan 28, 2009-ongoing; American Federation of Musicians. Local 802.
  Local 802 of the American Federation of Musicians is a local union of professional musicians living or working in New York City, Nassau and Suffolk counties, New York. The union's mission is to fight for the interests and well being of the musicians employed in New York's music and entertainment industries through organizing and collective bargaining as well as through legislative and political action. The website contains agreements and contracts, their Allegro magazine and other news postings, and event listings.
  Musicians |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada
  The American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM) is a labor union of professional musicians in the United States and Canada, founded in 1896. The AFM represents the interests of professional musicians by negotiating fair agreements, protecting ownership of recorded music, securing benefits such as health care and pension, and lobbying legislators.
  Musicians |x Labor unions |z United States.; Musicians--Labor unions--Canada.
- American Federation of School Administrators (AFSA) Archived Website, Dec 3, 2009 - ongoing; American Federation of School Administrators
  The American Federation of School Administrators (AFSA) is the national education union for school administrators, which provides labor relations and professional and occupational services to public school principals, vice principals, administrators and supervisors in diverse school districts across the U.S., Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands. Affiliated with the AFL-CIO, AFSA has been working for quality public school education for students of all backgrounds since 1976. AFSA’s mission is to promote the professional, occupational, and economic interests of its 20,000 members and work for the highest quality public school education for all pupils.
  Collective bargaining |x School administrators |z United States.
- American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) Archived Website, Dec 3, 2009 - ongoing; AFSCME.
  American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), founded in 1932, is a public services employees union with more than 1.6 million active and retired members, consisting primarily of workers in the local and state government and in the health care industry. AFSCME organizes for social and economic rights of their members in the workplace and through political action and legislative advocacy.
  Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 1707 Archived Website, Nov 28, 2012 - ongoing; AFSCME. District Council 1707.
  District Council 1707 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) is the only council within AFSCME that is chartered exclusively to represent private, nonprofit employees. It currently represents about 25,000 workers throughout the New York City area (and New York State), including those within private sector fundraising and advocacy agencies, case work and group work agencies, teaching and related organizations, child care centers, home care services, and Head Start programs. The website contains information on the political action committee, class and workshops, benefits, and news.
- American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.) Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.).
  District Council 37 (DC 37) is a local union of the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) which represents New York City public employees and employees in the healthcare industry. DC 37 was founded in 1944.
  Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37, Local 1930, New York Public Library Guild Archived Website, Jan 28, 2009 - ongoing; AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.).
  The New York Public Library Guild Local 1930, formed in 1968, represents almost 2,000 clericals, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and other titles. Members of Local 1930 are employed by the New York Public Library, by the City of New York in its branch libraries, and the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. The bargaining unit includes professional, non-professional and technical positions. As an activist union, they believe libraries are the backbone of democracy and unions are the vehicles to defend the economic rights of clerks, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and others.
  Librarians |z New York (State) |z New York.; Library employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37, Local 983 Archived Website, Mar 28, 2014-ongoing; AFSCME. Local 983.